（水影）この札で封印するんだな。
よし　いいぞ　風影の若いの。
So they'll use these tags to seal us.
All right!
Well done, young Kazekage!
ありゃ？
（雷影）ヌッ！
なんでだよ　おい！
What?
俺としては封印される気
満々なんだぞ。
What's going on?!
I'm totally ready to be sealed!
相手の術を
１度認識してしまうと→
Our bodies are programmed to
automatically counter an enemy's jutsu!
体が勝手にそれに対応するよう
プログラムされとる。
チッ。
（テマリ）来るぞ！
Here they come!
（みんな）うわぁ！
２人を囲め。
Surround those two!
（土影）塵遁。　原界剥離の術。
Particle Style…
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
ハァ　ハァ…。
（無）歳だな　オオノキ。
You've aged, Ohnoki.
Nonsense…
なんの。
ハァ　ハァ…。
You'd better get the Kazekage here
to use his sensory skills
（無）さっさと風影を呼んで
感知しなければ死ぬぞ　オオノキ。
or you'll die, Ohnoki!
The Mizukage, the Giant Clam
and the Mirage
おい　俺の術は　そりゃハンパねえから
もっと離れたほうがいいぞ。
マジで。
マジで？
Hey!
Don't underestimate my jutsu!
You really should stand back!
弱点は教えてやっから　マジで。
マジで？
For real!
マジで。　いいか　俺は隠遁。
For real?
Here are my weaknesses!
つまり幻術使いだ。
For real!
For real?
For real.
口寄せは…。
Now listen! I'm a Shadow Style user,
in other words, I use genjutsu.
オオハマグリだ。
（みんな）うわぁ。
And my summoning is…
わしは雷遁を使う。
a Giant Clam!
土遁の忍を前列に置き
盾を作りつつ→
風遁の忍で攻め立てろ。
I'm a Lightning User!
ごていねいにどうも。
できれば　もっと知りたいけどね。
Line up your Earth Style shinobi
and use them as a shield…
and attack with
your Wind Style shinobi!
体が勝手に動く。
ゆっくり話してる時間はない。
Thanks for your thoughtfulness!
In fact, I'd like to know more!
こい！
I have no control over my body!
風遁使いと土遁使いは私に続け。
I can't waste any more time talking!
Come!
封印班も遅れるな。
Wind and Earth Style shinobi,
follow me!
そうだよな。　行っちまいな　雷影。
Sealing Unit, keep up with us!
俺とお前が２人揃っていたら→
That's right. Go away, Raikage.
こいつらに封印なんか
できやしねえって。
If you and I stick together,
these guys won't be able to seal us.
で　策はできたか？　５代目　風影。
So, do you have a strategy…
Fifth Kazekage?
（我愛羅）お前たちにここを任せる。
えっ！
隊長！
隊長なしであいつを！
I'm leaving you guys in charge here.
おい　おいおい　おい！
なんだよ　その策は。
Huh?! Commander!
We have to deal with him
without you?!
いいか　俺は隠遁使いだって
言っただろうが。
Hey, hey! What kind of tactic is that?!
このオオハマグリは
広範囲幻術を使うんだ。
Didn't you hear me?!
I am a Shadow User!
幻を見せる。
物理攻撃はきかねえ！
This Giant Clam can cast
a genjutsu over a wide area!
It'll make you see illusions!
蜃気楼なんだよ！
A physical attack won't work!
（我愛羅）
あんたから殺気は感じられない。
I'm talking about a mirage!
そりゃそうだ。　当然だ。
I can tell.
You have no desire to kill.
術者の好きに操られてるなんて
不愉快でしようがねえ。
Of course not!
That's to be expected!
I can't stand being manipulated
by some other jutsu user.
だから　さっさと封印してくれ
ってんだよ風影！　って　おい！
That's why I want you to
seal me quickly, Kazekage! Hey!
頼むぞ！
（水影）おいって！
任せてください！
あんなチョビヒゲ！
Deal with him.
Hey!
チョビヒゲ…。
You can count on us!
Hey, wispy whiskers!
チョビヒゲ言うんじゃねえ！
穢土転生　関係なしに殺すぞ！
Wispy whiskers?
Don't call me that!
I don't care about
the Reanimation anymore. I'll kill you!
ぬぅ…。
うわっ　殺気だ！
あ～っ！
He means it!
やりにくい。
Man, this is awkward.
いくぞ　みんな！
（みんな）オーッ！
Let's go, guys!
やるぞ　みんな！
（みんな）オーッ！
– Yeah!
– Right!
Let's do it!
– Yeah!
– Right!
頼むぜ　なんとかしてくれよ！
I'm counting on you…
Do something.
（水影）よ～し
立派な面構えじゃねえか。
Good! Now you look like you
mean business!
いいか！
もういっぺん言っておくぞ！
Listen up, I'll tell you one more time!
今の俺を攻撃しても
無駄だからな！
Attacking this me is useless!
（無）お前に俺の感知はできない。
Your sensory skills are useless
against me.
わしをナメんでくだされ。
You shouldn't underestimate me.
岩分身の術！
Stone Clone Jutsu!
（無）数で来るか…
それもいいだろう。
So you'll come at me in numbers…
That might work.
Did we get him?
やった…　のか？
No way!
あぁ！
そんな～！
I told you attacking
this me is useless!
（水影）だから　今の俺を攻撃しても
無駄だって言ったよな　こら！
This me is just a mirage!
今の俺は蜃気楼だ！
Then what do we have to do?!
じゃあ　どうすればいいんです！？
So, defeat my Giant Clam first!
だからよぉ　まず　オオハマグリを倒せ！
It's the one creating the mirage.
こいつが蜃気楼を作ってるって
言ったよな！？
But its shell is hard.
Use large-scale weapons
or Paper Bombs!
殻は硬いぞ
大型の武器や起爆札を使え！
But…
What?
しかし…。
何だ！？
We just used them
with the last attack…
今の攻撃で…。
は？
さっさと武器を
回収しろって言ってんだよ！
す…　すみません。
みんな　急げ！
Just hurry up and
retrieve the weapons!
I'm sorry!
あぁ　それ　俺のだよ。
Everyone, quickly!
どこだ？　俺の武器。
Hurry!
おっと
向こうにも　いっぱいあるぞ！
Hey, that's mine.
Where's my weapon?
Hey! There are a lot of 'em
over that way too!
潮干狩りかよ…。
すみません　どうも。
やりにくい。
What are you doing here?
Digging for clams?
Pardon us.
よし！　やるぞ　みんな！
（みんな）オーッ！
This is awkward…
オオハマグリを狙え！
おりゃっ！
All right! Let's do it, everyone!
シャーッ！
– Right!
Target the Giant Clam!
（みんな）ハーッ！
Take that!
おぉ～！
やったか？
Did we get it?
あれ？
あぁ～　もう　やってらんねえな。
Huh?
なんで？
どうなってんだよ！？
Damn it! I can't stand this anymore!
いや　だから言ってる。
さっきから言ってる！
– Why?!
Hey! What's going on?
Yeah. So I keep telling you
over and over again…
あのオオハマグリも蜃気楼だ　バカ！
本物を狙えっつってんだろ！
That Giant Clam is also a mirage, idiots!
だから　本物は　どこなんです！？
Aim for the real one!
Yeah, so tell us where the real one is!
だから
俺の後ろ辺りに見えないように→
Like I said! Look around behind me!
蜃気楼で隠れてるって
言ってんだろ！
え～い　クソッ！
It's camouflaged within
a mirage and hiding!
Aww, damn it!
だから　今の俺を攻撃しても
無駄だっつってんだろ！
I told you attacking
this me is useless!
いや　後ろのオオハマグリを
狙ってるつもりで…。
Oh no, I was aiming for
the Giant Clam in the back.
だから
蜃気楼だっつってんだろ　バカ！
Like I said, that's a mirage, idiot!
もう　わかんないっすよ！
わかんないっすよ！
Aw man, I don't understand!
（みんな）わかんないっすよ！
あのな　お前ら…。
I don't get it!
– We don't get it!
Look, you guys…
チョビヒゲ！
殺す！
Wispy whiskers!
うわぁ！
殺気だ！
I'll kill you!
He means it!
早く謝れ！
早く　ほら！
– Who said that?! Apologize!
– Come out and apologize! Hurry!
すみません！
I'm sorry.
はぁ　やりにくい…。
This is awkward…
こうなったら
もう一度　総攻撃だ！
What the heck!
Once more, an all-out attack!
いくぞ～！
（みんな）お～っ！
Let's go!
いいのか？
お前ら　それでいいのか！？
Are you sure?
Are you really sure
you want to do that?!
クッ…　今のは　どこから？
Where did that come from?!
（我愛羅）後ろだ　土影！
Behind you, Tsuchikage!
Not now!
《こ…　こんなときに！》
塵遁！　原界剥離の術！
Particle Style!
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu.
《ん？　あれは…》
Is that…?!
Planet Rasengan!
《ナルト：惑星螺旋丸！》
《あれは…　ナルトか！？》
Is that…Naruto?!
クソッ！
無様は感知タイプじゃぜ。
Damn it!
Lord Mu is a Sensory Shinobi.
我愛羅！　砂！
Gaara!
Sand!
《砂を土台にして反撃か？
なるほどな》
Using Sand as a springboard
for his attack?
I see.
かわせ！
俺の術のほうが一瞬はやい！
Dodge this.
My jutsu is faster than yours!
おら～！
《よし！》
All right!
《これは…》
This is…
乱回転の螺旋丸だ！
a violently rotating…
Rasengan!
土遁　加重岩の術！
Earth Style… Boulder Jutsu!
Now you're so heavy,
これで　もう重すぎて
腕も上がりませんで。
you won't even be able to
raise your arms.
Owww…
あぁ　イタタ…。
他里嫌いのお前が→
You used to hate the other villages,
now you work so well with them.
やつらと
いいコンビネーションじゃないか。
It's worth living a long life.
長生きをしてみるもんですねぇ。
変化を楽しめる。
You get to enjoy change.
Don't let down your guard. I'm still…
用心しろ　俺は…。
All right! Way to go, Gaara!
よっしゃ～！
さすが　我愛羅　と→
Oh yeah…
Nice work too, Shorty Gramps!
あと　ちっせえじいちゃんも
ナイスだってばよ！
I am the Tsuchikage, you know.
わしゃ　土影じゃぜ。
ところで…。
By the way—
What are you doing
on the battlefield?!
なんで　お前が
こんな戦場にいる！？
Why did you come?!
Err…
なんで出てきた！？
あ…　いや～　えっと…。
Well…
Let me explain…
You better have a good enough
explanation to persuade me!
説明すっとだな…。
俺を納得させるだけの理由を
説明できるんだろうな？
That would be impossible.
So I will do the talking.
（シカク）そりゃあ　無理だ。
This is Shikaku Nara at HQ.
（シカク）だから　俺が話す。
本部の奈良シカクだ。
Both you and the Tsuchikage
were in the middle of fighting,
土影殿も風影殿も
戦闘中だったんで→
so I thought I'd save
the complicated talk for later.
Let's hear it then.
But the fighting is not over.
ややこしい話は
あとでと思ったんでね。
聞こう。　ただし
戦闘が終わったわけじゃない。
We must head out immediately.
You can brief us on the way.
すぐ次へ向かう。
移動中　手短に教えてくれ。
（水影）いや…　勝つ気は
まったくねえんだけどよ。
You know,
I'm not trying to win here.
うぅ…　強すぎだよ。
まぁ　なんだな　そんな俺でも
お前らに封印してもらわねえと→
You're too strong for us.
Yeah well…
Still, you must seal me.
操り人形のままなんでな。
ほら　立て　立て。
Otherwise, I'll remain a puppet…
Okay, everyone, get up! Get up!
（土影）そういうことか。
あの　雷影までもが
許可したとはな。
So that's how it is, eh?
I can't believe even
the Raikage relented.
よし　納得した。
（シカク）では　これで交信を切ります。
All right, I understand.
うむ。
I'm going to cease transmitting now.
（我愛羅）ナルト…　各戦場へ行き→
Naruto.
敵の変化を見分けるのはいいが→
I have nothing against going
from one battlefield to another
人柱力だった俺にはわかる。
to identify the enemy
using transformation.
But as a former Jinchuriki,
I know…
その九尾のチャクラ…
そんなに多用して→
The Nine Tails' chakra…
本当に大丈夫なのか？
Are you sure you can handle
using it so frequently?
俺は　火影になるまでは
死なねえつもりだ。
I don't plan on dying
until I become the Hokage.
もう　風影だからって　人のこと
子供扱いしてんじゃねえってばよ。
Don't treat me like a kid just
because you're the Kazekage now.
俺は　右の戦場。
I'll take the right battlefront!
我愛羅と　土影のじいちゃんは
左に行ってくれ。
Gaara and Gramps Tsuchikage,
take the left!
ナルト　向こうにいるのは
３代目　雷影だ。
Naruto, the Third Raikage is there!
わかった！
Got it!
わしらの相手は
２代目　水影じゃな。
And our opponent is
the Second Mizukage, correct?
幻術使いか…。
The Genjutsu User…
あぁ
一筋縄ではいかぬ相手じゃぞ。
Yes… Ordinary methods
won't work against him.
– Oh, man…
– Still?
だから　蜃気楼だっつってんの！
I keep telling you it's a mirage.
回収！
Go retrieve them!
I've had it.
おい　そこの！
Hey, you there!
Huh? You mean me?
は？　俺でしょうか？
You're from the Hidden Mist,
aren't you?
お前　霧隠れの忍だろうが。
Aren't you familiar with my jutsu?
俺の術のこと
知らねえのか？
I know little about you,
Lord Second.
２代目様のことは　何も…。
I mean, I only know about
the current Lord Fifth.
というか自分　今の
５代目様しか知りません。
かぁ～！　霧隠れの秘密主義の
弊害だな　こりゃ。
The secretiveness of
the Hidden Mist is to blame for this.
If I knew things would be like this,
こんなことなら　俺も　もっと
伝説を残しておけばよかったぜ。
I would've left behind
a bigger legend!
Not good…
やべえ…。
Hey, you there!
Playtime is over!
Come at me seriously now!
おい　お前ら！　遊びは終わりだ！
ここからは　本気でこい！
We have been serious!
これまでも
本気だったんですけど…。
I have no control over my body.
It's casting jutsu on its own.
体が　勝手に動くんだ。
術も　勝手に発動しやがる。
Damn it! I can't stand this!
うぅ　ムカつく！
不愉快きわまりねえ！
It's my Water Balloon Jutsu.
水風船の術だ。
上手くかわせよ！
Defend yourselves!
（みんな）うわぁ～！
あぁ！
Commander Gaara!
Huh? What took you so long?!
我愛羅隊長！
なんでえ　今ごろ戻って
きやがって。
I hope this time you'll seal me!
で　今度こそ
封印してくれんだろうな？
I intend to.
I'm looking forward to it.
そのつもりだ。
期待してるぜ。
Commander!
隊長！
（みんな）うわぁ～！
うわぁ～！
This is not the time to be
looking somewhere else!
うわぁ～！
よそ見してる場合じゃねえぞ！
（我愛羅）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
おい…。
Hey…
そんなもんかよ。
Is that all you got?
ハァ…　ハァ…。
弱点を教えてやってるのに
どいつもこいつも…。
I keep telling you my weaknesses,
yet every single one of you…
弱点がわかったところで
強すぎる。
You tell us, but you're still too strong!
ハァ…　ハァ…。
《これは水というより油に近いな。
This is closer to oil than water.
砂でガードしても
染み込んで滑り　崩れる》
Even if I use Sand as a barrier,
it'll just seep in and
make it collapse.
お前ら　先に無のほうへ行ったろ。
You went to tackle Mu first,
didn't you?
だいたいな　強そうなほうから
先に倒しにかかるもんだ→
You always want to go for
the stronger one first.
戦闘ってのは！
（我愛羅）だから　そうした。
That's what you call battle!
And that's what we did.
どう見たって
俺のほうが強そうだろうが！
Isn't it obvious I'm the stronger one?!
死にかけのミイラにしか
見えねえぞ　あいつは。　違うか！？
That guy looks like
a half-dead mummy. Am I right?
確かに…
人は見かけによらないとわかった。
True…
I realize now
that appearances can deceive.
あんたは強い。
You certainly are strong.
フッ…　ようやく理解を。
Finally, you understand.
Huh?! What do you mean
"appearances can be deceiving"?!
あれ…　おい！
見かけによらないってのは何だ！？
But you've got wispy whis—
だって　チョビヒ…。
よせ～っ！
Cut it out!
い…　今の俺は
オオハマグリが見せる広範囲幻術→
I told you…
that this me is a mirage,
created by the Giant Clam's
wide-range genjutsu.
蜃気楼だって
お前にも言ったよな。
So physical attacks are useless!
だから物理攻撃は効かねえぞ。
Find the Giant Clam quickly
and destroy it!
さっさと　オオハマグリを見つけて
潰さねえと　いつまで経っても…。
Otherwise, this will never end…
That's right. Your Sand…
あ！　そういや　お前　砂で…。
I like to let my actions
do the talking.
俺は　口より先に行動に移す。
Over there!
あそこじゃぜ。
So you were already searching
for it with your Sand.
もう砂の物理感知してやがったか。
I wondered why you were just focused
on the defensive.
どうりで防戦一方で
うわの空だと思ったぜ。
Well, finally a worthy foe!
ま　だとしたら　やっと→
まともなのが
相手になるってことだ。
Now hurry up and defeat me!
いいかげん俺を　やっつけやがれ！
I used too much chakra in
my fight against Lord Mu.
《無様との戦闘で
チャクラを使いすぎたな。
I can't use the Particle Style now.
Well, I have no choice.
さすがに塵遁は　もう無理か。
I have to smash it
into pieces myself!
こうなれば　しかたないのう。
Earth Style! Stone Fist Jutsu!
直接　叩き割るだけじゃぜ。
土遁　拳岩の術！》
One problem…
ただな…。
You've got to put your back
into it a bit more.
クッ…。
A light punch won't work, Lil' Ohnoki.
腰の入ってねえ軽いパンチじゃ
無理だぜ　オオノキの小僧。
You're not using
the Particle Style…
Have you run out of juice?
塵遁を使わねえとこ見ると
スタミナ切れか？
I'm not that Lil' Ohnoki
you used to make fun of long ago!
今は　小僧とバカにされてた昔とは
違うんじゃぜ！
Earth Style…
土遁　超加重岩の術！
オオノキ　やるじゃねえか！
《あぁ　やっちまったか…》
幻術が解けたか。
ぐあぁ…　腰が…。
お前が土影の名を受け継ぐのは
わかってたがな。
うっ…　ぐぅ…。
今じゃ　無理がたたって→
腰痛持ちのじじいに
成り下がってるじゃねえか。
腰の入った重いパンチに
変えたはいいが→
重すぎて腰がガッタガタ…　って！
おい　早く逃げろ。
鬼灯一族の水鉄砲の術だ。
ぐっ…。
こっちは止まらねえんだ！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージを　お届けいたします。